# Mikhail Stepanov

## Software Engineer

mikhail.stepanovv@yandex.ru

t.me/go\_on\_maggot\_brain





I am a backend (Java) software engineer with 4+ years of professional experience and passion for clean and performant code. I build distributed, robust and fault tolerant services for businesses. I'm also interested in ML (scikit-learn, pytorch) and mobile development (Flutter) in my free time.

## work experiences

#### Total - 4 years 9 months

**Software Engineer** Align Technology inc. | Full-time | 2020 - present Developed new microservices and enhanced backend systems for client-centric applications, such as the web page that manages patient care or API for clinical trials. Assigned as a scrum-master in the team who tracks activity, reviews sprints and release-cycles.

**Webinar Teacher**GeekBrains | Contractor | 2020 - 2021

Prepared and conducted lectures and homeworks on Java and Spring

Framework. Mentored students throughout the course.

**Java Developer**Business Environment | Full-time | 2019 - 2020

Developed the backend for an educational online-platform. Designed microservice architecture, participation in task scheduling and code reviews.

## **Junior Java Developer** *E-COM* | *Full-time* | 2019 - 2019 Developed the backend for the enterprise, document management

system for retail. Designed microservices and the architecture.

**Performance Test Engineer** Aplana Software | Full-time | 2017 - 2019 Made scripts in C, servlets and web services (stubs) in Java. Created test cases, carried out load testing for banking software and analysis of the results.

### links



github.com/mikhail-stepanov



linkedin.com/in/mikhail-stepanovv



mikhail-stepanov.com

## skills

#### Hard

Java, Spring, JPA (Hibernate)
PostgreSQL, S3, Redis
Kafka, RabbitMQ, Kinesis
Docker, k8s, Terraform
Microservices, AWS, Heroku
Splunk, Zabbix, Grafana, ELK

#### Soft

Release Management Task Management Sprint Planning Scrum-master

## education

**MSc. Business Informatics** HSE, Moscow, Russia

2020 - 2022

#### **Exchange Student**

BTU, Cuttbus, Germany 2019 - 2020

# BSc. Computer Science HSE, Moscow, Russia

2016 - 2020

## languages

Russian - native

**English - advanced** 

German - intermediate